Based on truly possible events.
Don't Look Up is a comedy, science fiction, drama film directed by Adam McKay.
Two astronomers go on a media tour to warn humankind of a
planet-killing comet hurtling toward Earth.
The response from a distracted world: Meh.
Dr. Randall Mindy, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Kate Dibiasky, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
President Orlean, played by Meryl Streep.
Brie Evantee, played by Cate Blanchett.
Dr. Teddy Oglethorpe, played by Rob Morgan.
Jason Orlean, played by Jonah Hill.
Don't Look Up is a 2021 American political satire black comedy film written, co-produced,
and directed by Adam McKay from a story he co-wrote with David Sirota.
It stars an ensemble cast featuring Leonardo DiCaprio, Jennifer Lawrence, Rob Morgan, Jonah Hill, Mark Rylance,
Tyler Perry, Timothée Chalamet, Ron Perlman, Ariana Grande, Kid Cudi, Cate Blanchett, and Meryl Streep.
In the film, it tells the story of two astronomers attempting to warn humanity
about an approaching comet that will destroy human civilization.
The movie's central comet impact event was used by McKay as an
allegory for threats arising from climate change.
The film satirizes government, political, celebrity, and media indifference, in particular to the climate
crisis, but with further synergy with regard to responses to science during the COVID-19 pandemic.
Produced by McKay's Hyperobject Industries and Bluegrass
Films, the film was announced in November 2019.
Originally set for a theatrical release by Paramount Pictures, the
distribution rights were acquired by Netflix several months later.
Lawrence became the first member of the cast to join, with DiCaprio signing on after his discussions
with McKay on adjustments to the script; the rest of the cast was added through 2020.
Filming was initially set to begin in April 2020 in Massachusetts, but it was delayed due to the
COVID-19 pandemic; it eventually began in November 2020 and wrapped in February 2021.
Don't Look Up began a limited theatrical release on December 10,
2021, before streaming on Netflix on December 24.
It was praised for the cast's performances and the musical score, but critics were divided on the merits of
McKay's satire: some found it deft, while others criticized it as smug and heavy-handed.
Donna Lu of The Guardian notes that the movie "received a frosty reception from many
film critics", while being thoroughly lauded by climate activists.
Don't Look Up was named one of the top ten films of 2021 by the
National Board of Review and American Film Institute.
It received four Academy Award nominations (including Best Picture), four Golden Globe Award nominations (including Best Picture – Musical or Comedy), six
Critics' Choice Award nominations, (including Best Picture), and also won Best Original Screenplay at the 74th Writers Guild of America Awards.
The film set a new record for the most viewing hours in a single week on Netflix, and went on
to become the second-most-watched movie on Netflix within 28 days of release.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence (a.i.), the
white house, asteroid, climate change, satire.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.